RG 039, Flood Recovery Committee
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Flood Recovery Committee records
1955-1956
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Flood Recovery Committee
2.5 cubic feet
Following the disastrous flood of August 19, 1955, called the "worst flood in the history of eastern United States," Governor Abraham Ribicoff appointed a twenty-member committee to study the immediate problems to be faced and to recommend a program of rehabilitation.
RG039
T002694
Historical Note
In response to the flood of August 1955, Governor Abraham Ribicoff appointed a twenty-member committee to study emergency needs and immediate recovery problems and recommend a program of rehabilitation. The Committee, appointed August 27, 1955, was headed by Sherman R. Knapp. Ten meetings of the Committee and its Coordinating Group were held, as well as numerous meetings of the five sub-committees. The final report, submitted on November 3, 1955, recommended a 35 million dollar program of state aid to flood victims and towns, repair and replacement of state-owned property, and planning for redevelopment.
Scope and Content
This group contains subject files pertaining to the work of the Committee, other State committees working on the same problem, a coordinating committee and five subcommittees, publicity, and the final report. Files contain minutes, correspondence, lists of commercial businesses damaged, reports, newspaper clippings, and other reference materials.
Related Material
RG 005:033, Abraham Ribicoff gubernatorial records.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut Flood Recovery Committee
Subjects:
Connecticut Flood Recovery Committee -- Records and correspondence; Floods -- Connecticut; Flood damage -- Connecticut; Disaster relief -- Connecticut -- Finance; Hurricane Diane -- 1955
Document Types:
Clippings; Correspondence; Minutes; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1955-1956
  - 1. General file, 1955 August-1956 January
    Contains correspondence, minutes of meetings, reference materials, newspaper clippings, notes and memoranda pertaining to the flood damage, the work of the Committee and its recommendations.
    Arranged by subject.
    - General (Box 1)
    - Organization (Box 1)
      - General (Box 1)
      - Subcommittees (Box 1)
    - Subcommittees (Box 1)
      - Aid to flood victims (Box 1)
      - Housing (Box 1)
      - Legislative (Box 2)
      - Reconstruction planning (Box 2)
      - State reconstruction costs (Box 2)
    - Other state committees (Box 2)
      - Connecticut Development Commission (Box 2)
      - Connecticut Public Expenditure Council (Box 2)
    - Meetings (Box 2)
      - General (Box 2)
      - Main Committee (Box 2)
      - Coordinating Committee (Box 2)
      - Subcommittees (Box 2)
      - Secretary's copy (Box 2)
    - Publicity (Box 3)
      - General (Box 3)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 3)
        - 1955 August-1955 October (Box 3)
        - 1955 November-1956 January (Box 4)
        - Reproduced newspaper clippings, 1955 (Box 5)
    - Reports (Box 5)
      - Report to Governor (Box 5)
        Includes copy of printed
        Report of the Connecticut Flood Recovery Committee to Governor Abraham Ribicoff, 1955 November 3, p. 61.
      - Subcommittee (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 5)